ERNESTO VALECILLOS

Houston, TX | 346-588-2200 | evalecillos@gmail.com | Linkedin: evalecillos | GitHub: evalecillos | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in computer hardware repair as well as production leadership and mentorship with a passion for learning new knowledge and skills. Proficient and experienced working and leading a team and swiftly able to adapt to find solutions to any issues. Excited to grow and excel as a developer.

SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JSON, JavaScript, Git, React, Redux, MUI, SQL, Java, NoSQL, Heroku, jQuery, GraphQL, MERN Stack, Test-Driven Development, Web & Server API's, Object-Relational Mapping, Progressive Web Applications, Object-Oriented Programming, MVC Design Pattern.

PROJECTS

Spoiler-Alert - GitHub: spoiler-alert | Live Link: spoiler-alert

Message board app that requires users to be logged in to read spoilers on a given movie/show

- Back-end dev for a team of 4. Focused on database management & models and connecting to the front-end.
- Tools: JavaScript, Node.is, Sequelize, MySQL, Express.is, Handlebars, Bootstrap.

Shop-Shopdux - GitHub: shop-shopdux | Live Link: shop-shopdux

Single page web app that also stores data if user is offline to enhance user experience.

- · React application built first using Context API, then refactored to use Redux instead.
- Tools: React, Redux, Apollo Client, Stripe API, IndexedDB.

Gale-Weather-App - GitHub: gale-weather-app | Live Link: gale-weather-app

Single page web app where users can save favorited cities and track their weather's various properties. Integrated OpenWeather API.

- Front-end dev for a team of 5. Focused on website view, styling and component creation with a new technology (MUI).
- Tools: JavaScript, React, Context API, Material UI, Apollo Client, MongoDB, Express.js

EXPERIENCE

MLB Engineer Technician II, CSAT Solutions, Houston, TX I August 2021-Current

- Reduced component expenses by 50%
- Decreased backlog by 67% via implementing BOM component order system.
- Implemented 5S standard across technicians.
- Provided troubleshooting support to whole unit repair as well as MLB department.

Lenovo Flat Panel Display Lead, CSAT Solutions, Houston, TX I July 2020-August 2021

- Boosted daily claim fulfillment output by 250%.
- Implemented inventory system boosting accuracy to 99%.
- Built BCR increasing Cx report accuracy, shipping output by 45%, & part accuracy by 65%.
- Increased repair efficiency by 25% and reduced labor cost by 30%.

Lenovo WUR Technician Lead, CSAT Solutions, Houston, TX I November 2019-July 2020

- Trained 90+ technicians in repair & testing processes & troubleshooting techniques...
- Neutralized backlog and increased output by 100%.
- Reduced end-customer escalations by 70%.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp certificate for Full Stack Web Development, University of Texas at Austin, TX

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Representational State Transfer, SQL Databases, React, Redux, MongoDB, Express.js, Node.js, Object Oriented Programming & Progressive Web Applications.